The time is 6:30 in the morning December 1
1948. On the outskirts
by the city of Adelaide in Australia
At a place called Somerton Beach discovers some people at the beach
A dead man.
The police were called and blocked off the area.
The dead man lay on his back in the sand.
had no wounds or injuries.
He was 180 centimeters long.
Gray eyes, reddish brown hair that had begun to turn gray
in the temples.
Between 40 to 50 years old
And weighed about 80 kilos.
All the labels on his clothes had been removed.
What the man was wearing in his pockets was as follows:
1 unused train ticket from Adelaide to Henley Beach.
1 bus ticket from Adelaide that was not used.
1 narrow aluminum comb made in the United States.
1 half -empty package with Juicy Fruit chewing gum.
That it was the same person.
The man's fingerprints gave no hit
in the police register, he did not seem to have a criminal past.
The autopsy of the body began a few days
after it was discovered and the forensic doctor noted
That the man's shoes were remarkably clean and recently plastered,
Which was unexpected for a man found on a beach.
No obvious signs of violence or trauma were found.
Instead indicated some signs of
that the cause of death could be poisoning,
But one could not find any poison in the body
and there was no clear evidence of vomiting or cramps,
which are common bodily reactions to poisoning.
So the shoes were clean and polished ..
No signs of violence and the man had not vomited any poison ..
May the man have died somewhere else
And then been moved to the beach?
In December the same year,
As a last resort to try to identify the unknown man
Made the police a plaster cast of the man's face and bonfire.
This casting would become a central part of the investigation
and used several times for a possible identification of the man.
Although a definitive cause of death could not be determined
was the mystery far from over.
There was still no clue about who the man was or
Why he died under these strange circumstances.
The forensic doctor and the police were facing more questions
even answers and it soon became clear
That this case was far from the ordinary.
into the storage on November 30.
1948, thus the day
before the man had been found dead by the beach.
Inside the bag were found several different things.
A bathrobe,
A pair of slippers, underwear, pajamas and shaving articles.
Pants.
An electrician chisel
A modified table knife and a pair of scissors.
A stencil brush.
A wire short with orange waxed wire of the brand Barbour
And clothing with the tag T.Keane.
Keane.
And just Kean without an E at the end.
Also three dry cleaning markings.
1171/7, 4393/7
3053/7
All other labels on the clothes had been removed.
Just like with the dead man on the beach.
The markings with T.Keane
Keane and Kean were of great interest to the police.
They tried to track a person named T.Keane
But they found no records of any missing person with that name,
In June
1949, they examined the man's clothes again
And found a hidden pocket inside the man's pants.
Inside the pocket there was a small patch
And that seemed to be out of a book.
Upon closer examination, it turned out that the patch had been sewn
into the hidden pocket with an orange thread.
The same thread they had found in the suitcase earlier.
On the patch the words stood
Tamám Shud
No one within the police
Rubáiyát of Omar Khayyám
is a collection of poems of the Persian mathematician,
Astronomer and poet Omar Khayyám who lived on the thousands.
Rubáiyát is a term from the Persian poetry that means
"Kvatriner", which is a type of poem written with four lines.
The book was well known, but finding the right edition, as the note may have been driven from,
turned out to be a challenge.
They began to search all bookstores and libraries in Adelaide
And nearby cities, but without success.
When it did not give any success, they asked the public about
help where they showed off the book they were looking for
And the specific font contained by the book.
And finally, the police were a little luck.
July 22, 1949
came a man to the police with a copy of
Rubáiyát he had found in his brother -in -law's car.
He said someone had thrown the book into the rear seat of the car through a
Open window November 30, 1948,
While it was parked a block away from Somerton Beach
All signs pointed out that it
Here the copy of the poetry book was the book from which the paper was brought.
The police browse up to the correct side
In the book and there it was a hole,
Just as if someone has ripped out some of it.
The police brought out the torn note with the text Tamám Shud
And very real,
They fit like two perfect puzzle pieces.
Although the mystery of the stirred patch was now loose
So the book had more secrets to reveal.
Inside the book were found two very interesting things.
A phone number written on the back of the book in pencil
and also a mysterious pattern of letters.
If we start with the phone number, who belonged to it?
Police quickly discovered that the phone number was unlisted,
but managed to track it to a residence
that lay on Mosley Street in Glenelg
About 400 meters north of where the body was found.
The dwelling belonged to a young woman
named Jessica Thomson, 27 years.
She worked as a nurse and was married to a man named Prosper Thomson.
She was taken to the wedding house for
To consider the plaster casting of the man's face and bonfire.
When she saw the casting her breathing stopped.
The color disappeared from her face.
She looked to be on the verge of fainting.
It was a very strong reaction, especially for someone who was a nurse
during the war and certainly seen much worse things
than a plaster cast of a dead body.
The investigators concluded that her reaction was due to
Some form of emotional connection to the deceased man.
When it came to the book
Rubáiyát and why her phone number was written on the back she admitted that she previously
owned a copy she gave to a soldier named Alfred Boxall
in Sydney during wartime.
She did not reveal specific details about their relationship,
But the investigators suspected that it could have been a romantic connection.
What this alfred boxall the
did the somertonman die by the beach?
And was he a lover for Jessica Thomson?
One theory was that Alfred had chosen to end his life
After he could never win Jessica's heart altogether.
But this theory was quickly allowed to close down.
Alfred Boxall was discovered to be alive
and he had also retained his copy
by Rubáiyát as he had received from Jessica and in that book
Had no one torn out the words you have driven.
This track had to be put on ice.
And then we had the mysterious letters.
The pattern consisted of five rows with seemingly random letters,
One of the lines was overlined.
Was this a coded message?
And if so, who had written it?
And what did it mean?
Investigators had no idea and code experts were called in
To help solve the cryptic puzzle.
But try after attempt failed.
The code message in Rubáiyát has fascinated
and frustrated code crusher for over 70 years.
The five rows of apparently random letters are challenging
Still the best cryptographers in the world.
Is this a personal memory method?
A kind of cryptic poem?
Or maybe instructions for a secret assignment?
Nobody knows.
But it is, among other things, this particular mystery that has
Keep the mystery with the Somertonman alive.
Each generation takes on the challenge of solving it
in the hope of finally giving answers to the riddle
about who the unknown man really was.
For in spite of all these years of
surveys, despite the countless hours of research,
theories and guesses, is still a
As followed, a lot of different theories have emerged.
In early January 1949 identified
two people the body as 63 -year -old
Robert Walsh, a former loggers
Walsh had left Adelaide several months earlier to buy
Sheep in Queensland, but had not returned to Christmas as planned.
But the hands of the somerton were Lena and soft
And they indicated that he did not cut any trees for at least 18 months.
and that Walsh had a specific scar on the body
that the Somertonman did not have.
Another theory was that the Somertonman was a
Sailor named Tommy Reade from the ship SS Cycle
which was in port at the time when the body was found.
Possibly of Soviet descent,
who was in Australia during the Cold War.
This theory arose because of the mysterious circumstances surrounding his death.
The unidentifiable code in Rubáiyát
and that no one seems to have known him,
and that the labels of his clothes were missing,
Which was common for spies.
In November 1953
The police announced that they received over 250 “solutions” (tips) to the body's identity
from the public who claimed that they either met or felt him.
But none of the clues led anywhere.
It would take until July 26, 2022 when one
Finally had a breakthrough in the case.
The Somertonman had been buried a long time ago.
But inside the plaster cast of the Somertonman found small hairs
and through them one could implement a DNA
Analysis and genealogy.
And then you got a hit ..
The man on the beach was identified as
An electrical engineer and instrument manufacturer.
Born November 16, 1905 in Melbourne, Australia.
Carl Charles Webb was the youngest of sex
Children to Richard and Eliza Webb.
He came from simple conditions but worked his way up to become a skilled professional.
In 1941 he married Dorothy Robertsson,
A pharmacist and foot therapist.
The marriage was messy, characterized by Carl's difficult personality,
Dorothy described Karl as a lone man with few friends who lived
A withdrawn life and went to bed at seven every night.
He could seem calm, but his mood could swing vigorously
man to determine that Dorothy lived in the city of Bute
144 kilometers from Adelaide.
Maybe it might have been so that Carl had gone
to Adelaide with the intention of trying to find her.
Nobody knows.
Even though the mystery
with the Somertonman's identity was resolved
So there were still unanswered questions with the case.
Why did he have the patch with the text
Tamám Shud sewn into his pants?
What did the mysterious letters mean on the back of Rubáiyát